<?xml version="1.0"?>

<!-- This is a property metadata file. This file defines the
property metadata, such as polite names, data types, etc. -->
<property-metadata>
	<propertyfile>
		<file-description>
			This property file sample contains information about the world.

			The keys specify geographic locations in a tree-like format,
			from generic to particular.
		</file-description>
	</propertyfile>

	<!-- The default section allows you to specify defaults for any property
		that is not explicitly defined here -->
	<default datatype="string">
		<!-- This is the default description of a single property -->
		<description>Geographic location</description>

		<!-- This is the default description for a group of properties -->
		<group-description>Geographic Locations</group-description>

	</default>

	<property name="world">
		<group-description>The world</group-description>
	</property>

	<property name="world.continent">
		<group-description>The continents</group-description>
	</property>

	<property name="world.continent.America">
		<description>
			America, rediscovered in 1492 by Christopher Columbus
		</description>
		<group-description>
			Countries and Territories in the American continent.
		</group-description>
	</property>

	<property name="world.continent.Mexico">
		<group-description>
			States within the Mexican republic.
		</group-description>
		<description>
			Mexico, the country with the longest continous history on the
			American continent. Originally the empire of the Mexica (Aztecs),
			it was conquered by Hernan Cortez in 1521 and became the seat of
			government for the Spanish holdings in America, which extended
			from Oregon to Tierra del Fuego.

			Started a declaration of of independence and slave freedom in 1810,
			sparking the war of independence, which ended in victory and
			recognition of Mexico's independence in 1821.

			Mexico suffered a bloody history of war after that, which included
			civil wars, secession (Guatemala first, then Texas), foreign
			invasions (by Napoleonic France and the United States), and finally
			a full-scale revolution in 1910. The revolution ended in 1921 with the
			establishment of a state party, called the PNR first and then
			renamed the PRI. This party stayed on by instituting a mock
			democracy with rigged elections for over 70 years, which corrupted
			the government but at least allowed for an
			extended period of peace.

			In 1999 the party was toppled in free and peaceful elections,
			promising a new beginning for the country. The PRI party today
			remains an important, if ideology-lacking political force.
		</description>
	</property>

	<property name="world.continent.USA">
		<description>
			The United States of America. The world's most stable democratic
			republic, and biggest world power. Referred to by the english-speaking
			world simply as "America".

			Originally a collection of 13 British and dutch colonies ruled by
			Great Britain, the colonies were formed mostly by christian
			congregations like Quakers, Puritans and Catholics fleeing religious
			persecution in europe. When there was nothing but bare land, the
			colonists started their own small governments basing themselves on
			british Common Law. After the colonies reached a certain size and
			importance, the British levied heavy taxes and restrictions on the
			colonies without local representation, violating the 12th century's
			Magna Carta - the basic law of all the British countries -
			established by King Richard.

			This galvanized the dreams of independence of the seemingly
			disparate colonies against a common enemy. A declaration of
			independence was signed in 1776, starting the war of Independence.

			With the support of France and Spain (enemies of Britain at the
			time), the United States achieved recognition within Europe and was
			able to trade with European partners early.


		</description>
	</property>

</property-metadata>
